fidgit.com 2010-12-06

# Privacy Policy | Syfy

## Effective as of July 7. 2009

## Introduction

This Web site, located at the domain syfy.com (the "Site") is operated by Syfy, a unit of NBC Universal ("NBCU" or "we" or "our" or "us"). Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information collected from you, what we do with it, with whom we share it, and how you can correct or change such information. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy carefully, especially before providing any personal data through the Site. This Site is operated in and controlled from the United States of America. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or Site, or if you wish to unsubscribe from Site services for which you have previously registered, please contact us at [feedback@syfy.com](mailto:feedback@syfy.com) or at the address at the end of this policy. 

**PLEASE REVIEW THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE TERMS OF SERVICE FOR THE SITE CAREFULLY. YOUR USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR AGREEMENT TO SUCH PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF SERVICE.**

## Table of contents

  1. Types of Information Collected
    * Personal Data
    * Aggregate and Anonymous Data
  2. Use of Cookies and Other Technologies
  3. Our Use of Your Information
  4. Disclosure of Personal Data to Third Parties
    * Disclosure to Affiliates
    * Disclosure to Third Parties
    * Disclosure to Others
  5. Third Party Advertising and Links to Other Sites
  6. Your Choice
  7. Access and Correction
  8. Children and Privacy
  9. Message Boards, Chat Rooms, Blogs and Other User Forums
  10. Data Security
  11. Exclusions
  12. Other Terms and Conditions
  13. Site Location
  14. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  15. Contacting NBCU Regarding Your Privacy

## 1\. Types of Information Collected:

**Personal Data:** Personally Identifiable Information ("Personal Data") is any information that can be used to identify a specific individual, such as your name, e-mail address, home address, phone number and credit card information. This Site collects Personal Data when you interact with the Site - for example, when you subscribe for newsletters; register for membership services, such as chat rooms or message boards; participate in chat rooms, blogs or other user forums; respond to polls or surveys; purchase merchandise via the Site; register for sweepstakes, contests and other promotional opportunities; or seek help from our customer service departments. We also may collect information when you purchase products or services offline, or register for wireless services via your cell phone or other wireless devices ("Other Services"). Because providing detailed information regarding our Privacy Policy when you register or provide information in connection with these Other Services often proves impractical, you may instead be provided with a short notice that reminds you to refer to this Privacy Policy and other relevant information from us. We may also obtain Personal Data from reputable third parties, such as credit agencies. 

**Aggregate and Anonymous Data:** Aggregate and anonymous data is information that does not identify you specifically; this includes data collected automatically through the operation of the Site ("AA Data"). We may collect site-usage data (such as which Site pages you visit and in what sequence) through the use of various technologies. For example, we collect IP addresses from individuals who visit the Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the Web. Web servers - the computers that serve up Web pages - automatically identify your computer by its IP address, and when you request a page from the Site, its servers log your IP address. We do not link IP addresses to any Personal Data, so although your session will be logged, you will remain anonymous to us and the Site. We may also collect password information from you when you log in, as well as computer and connection information such as browser type or version. During some visits, we may use software tools, such as JavaScript, to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, time spent on certain pages, page-interaction information, and methods used to browse away from the page. 

## 2\. Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies:

Like many sites, we use "cookies" or other similar technologies to collect AA Data. A cookie is a small data file that is written to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes when you visit the Site. Cookies allow the Site to measure traffic activity on the Site and to improve your user experience - for example, by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, enabling you to visit "member only" portions of the Site without re-registering, and tracking the progress and number of entries in activities that require registration or entry, such as sweepstakes. Similarly, if you have asked us to send you information about upcoming products and promotions, using cookies to collect information about which Site pages you have visited and in what order ("Clickstream Data") may allow us to narrow or limit the materials provided to you based on your prior online activities or preferences. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent, but it is possible that some parts of the Site will not function properly if you do so. 

In addition, we may use a service that collects data remotely by using so-called "Pixel Tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" or similar means (collectively, "Pixel Tags") embedded in the Site's content. A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel (1 picture element by 1 picture element), that is ordinarily not visible to Site visitors and may be associated with cookies on the visitors' hard drives. This information is AA data. 

## 3\. Our Use of Your Data:

Like many sites, we use "cookies" or other similar technologies to collect AA Data. A cookie is a small data file that is written to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes when you visit the Site. Cookies allow the Site to measure traffic activity on the Site and to improve your user experience - for example, by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, enabling you to visit "member only" portions of the Site without re-registering, and tracking the progress and number of entries in activities that require registration or entry, such as sweepstakes. Similarly, if you have asked us to send you information about upcoming products and promotions, using cookies to collect information about which Site pages you have visited and in what order ("Clickstream Data") may allow us to narrow or limit the materials provided to you based on your prior online activities or preferences. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent, but it is possible that some parts of the Site will not function properly if you do so. 

In addition, we may use a service that collects data remotely by using so-called "Pixel Tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" or similar means (collectively, "Pixel Tags") embedded in the Site's content. A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel (1 picture element by 1 picture element), that is ordinarily not visible to Site visitors and may be associated with cookies on the visitors' hard drives. This information is AA data. 

## 4\. Disclosure to Affiliates:

**Disclosure of Personal Data:** We reserve the right to share Personal Data with our affiliates. If you do not want us to share your Personal Data with our affiliated companies for their marketing purposes, you may opt-out of such sharing by contacting us at [feedback@syfy.com](mailto:feedback@syfy.com) (see "Your Choices" below) 

**Disclosure to Third Parties:** We, like many businesses, sometimes hire other companies to perform certain business-related functions on our behalf, such as hosting specific portions of the Site, maintaining databases, administering contests, providing wireless services, mailing information and processing payments. When we employ a third party to perform these functions, that third party will be provided only with the particular Personal Data it needs to perform its function, and it is required to protect such Personal Data. For third-party-sponsored sweepstakes, contests or promotions, we may request Personal Data from you that may be shared with the sponsor upon request. With your consent, we may also share Personal Data with pre-screened third parties for their marketing or promotional purposes. We will provide you with an opportunity to elect or decline these services or opportunities. In the event you elect to unsubscribe from any of our services, we will share your Personal Data with third parties with whom we jointly offer such services solely to the extent necessary to ensure that your request not to receive such communications is honored. In addition, for third-party sponsored sweepstakes, contests or promotions, we may request Personal Data from you that may be shared with the sponsor upon request.

 **Disclosure to Others:** In addition, we may disclose Personal Data without providing you with a choice under the following limited circumstances to: (1) protect the legal rights, privacy or safety of NBCU, or its subsidiaries, affiliates or its or their employees, agents and contractors; (2) protect the safety and security of visitors to our Web sites or other properties; (3) protect against fraud or other illegal activity or for risk-management purposes; (4) respond to inquiries or requests from public authorities; (5) permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain; (6) enforce our Terms of Service; or (7) comply with the law or legal process. 

If NBCU sells all or part of this Site or makes a sale or transfer of assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, we may, in our sole discretion, transfer, sell or assign your Personal Data to a third party as part of or in connection with that transaction. Upon such transfer, the Privacy Policy of the acquiring entity may govern the further use of your Personal Data. 

## 5\. Third-Party Advertising and Links to Other Sites:

This Site may include third-party advertising. These third parties' Web sites and advertisers, or the Internet advertising companies that work on their behalf, may use technology to send (or "serve") the advertisements that appear on our Site directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use cookies, JavaScript, Pixel Tags and other technologies to deliver advertisements, collect information about the effectiveness of their advertisements, and to collect anonymous information about your visits to the Site, such as the number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address, or other Personal Data). For more information about these specialized cookies and other technologies, and how to "opt out" of information collection by these companies, we suggest you visit <http://doubleclick.net/privacy_policy> or <http://networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>. 

Please note that this Site contains links to other sites that will not follow the same Privacy Policy as our Site. For instance, clicking on an advertisement or on links or other elements on the Site may take you to an entirely different site. Links to other sites may use our Site logo or style as a result of a co-branding agreement. These sites may send their own cookies to you and may collect data and make use of that data in ways that this Site would not. Once you've left this Site, this Privacy Policy will no longer apply to Personal Data or any other data collected from or provided by you. You should check the applicable privacy policy to determine how that site will handle such data. 

## 6\. Your Choices:

You can use the Site and certain Other Services without providing any Personal Data, but if you decline to provide Personal Data, you may not be able to use certain services or features. If you have previously provided Personal Data to the Site and have subscribed to one or more e-mail newsletters or are receiving e-mails or other communications from the Site and you do not want to receive such e-mails, please discontinue your subscriptions by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any message, visiting the Members section of the Site or contacting us at [feedback@syfy.com](mailto:feedback@syfy.com). You may opt-out of receiving offers from us by adjusting your Site preferences at our Newsletter Signup link at the bottom of the home page. If you ask that we stop using your Personal Data, we will honor that request. However, we will retain records of your Personal Data as needed in order to comply with applicable federal, state, or local law. 

## 7\. Access and Correction:

If you would like to review, correct or change the Personal Data that you have previously provided us, please go to the Members section of the Site and follow the appropriate instructions or contact us at [feedback@syfy.com](mailto:feedback@syfy.com). We will take reasonable steps to update or correct Personal Data in our possession. 

## 8\. Children and Privacy:

We encourage parents and guardians to spend time with their children online and to be fully familiar with the sites visited by their children. At various places on the Site or Other Services, we may ask users for their age. By using the Site or Other Services you agree to respond truthfully and accurately about your age. Children younger than 13 years of age are expressly prohibited from submitting or posting any Personal Data on the Site or Other Services. 

## 9\. Message Boards, Chat Rooms, Blogs and Other User Forums:

Please remember that information posted to message boards, chat rooms, blogs and other user forums becomes public information. Use caution when posting. Individuals under the age of 18 should be especially careful not to provide any personally identifiable information when participating in any area of the Site where postings might become public. Please see our Terms of Service for the standards of behavior that must be followed when using these portions of the Site or Other Services. 

## 10\. Data Security Disclaimer:

NBCU takes reasonable security precautions to secure the Personal Data that you choose to provide against the loss, misuse, alteration or unauthorized access of such information. Unfortunately, no transmission of data over the Internet is guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of Syfy.com to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully. While we strive to protect your Personal Data, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any Personal Data you transmit to us. Any such transmission is done at your own risk. If you believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please notify us of the problem by contacting us at [feedback@syfy.com](mailto:feedback@syfy.com). 

## 11\. Exclusions:

This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to us on or through this Site or Other Services. Please see our Terms of Service for our policies regarding such Unsolicited Information. All such Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential, and NBCU shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose and distribute such Unsolicited Information to others without limitation or attribution. 

## 12\. Other Terms and Conditions:

Your access to and use of this Site or Other Services is subject to the Terms of Service. 

## 13\. Applicable Law:

Your access to and use of this Site or Other Services is subject to the Terms of Service. 

## 14\. Changes to this Privacy Policy:

From time to time, we may revise this Privacy Policy to reflect industry initiatives, changes in the law or technology, or changes in our practices regarding information collection and use. If we make revisions to the way we collect or use Personal Data, we may provide notice of those changes by either: (1) announcing the change on the home page of the Site or (2) taking such other action as we deem appropriate under the circumstances, including, without limitation, posting the revised draft of this Privacy Policy on the Site. You can determine when this Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the "Last Updated" legend at the top of this page. Any changes to this policy will become effective upon posting of the revised Privacy Policy on the Internet, accessible through the Site. By continuing to use the Site following such changes, you will be deemed to have agreed to such changes. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time, in whole or in part, please do not continue using this Site. 

## 15\. Contacting Syfy.com Regarding Your Privacy:

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, Personal Data gathered by this Site or Other Services, or about the operation of this Site or Other Services, or if you wish to unsubscribe from the Site or Other Services, please contact us at [feedback@syfy.com](mailto:feedback@syfy.com), or at the address listed below. 

Syfy.com  
30 Rockefeller Plaza, 21st Fl.  
New York, N.Y. 10112
